[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 38]
For your sake,
I won't be too hard on them.
I'll give you three days
to think it over carefully.
Take care, Lord Lai.
Nerd!
Nerd.
Stop crying, Chuichui.
I'm okay.
I'm alright.
Xing.
You can't keep skipping meals.
Open the door.
I've brought you some soup.
If you have any grievances,
once you've eaten,
I'll accompany you to storm the Shen's Mansion.
I, your mother,
have nearly died once before.
Whether it's the White Ghost
or the White King of Hell,
I
will surely scratch him until he cries for his parents.
My dear daughter.
I know you're suffering inside.
But as women,
we must be nourished
by love and appreciation.
He's a man who doesn't know how to appreciate you.
What use is he?
We can't let every little thing
knock us down, can we?
I promise you,
I'll definitely find you someone
who will cherish and protect you,
a handsome young man who will listen to your every word.
How does that sound?
Handsome young man?
I'm here to check on Yan Xing.
Xing!
It's me,
Pan Chi.
Xing!
Xing has been keeping to herself lately.
She won't open the door for anyone.
Come in.
So... She's taken my words to heart?
First Madam!
Ms. Jin.
Did a male outsider
just enter Xing's room?
First Madam, what nonsense are you talking about?
What do you mean by "male outsider"?
Our Xing is a female official in the Ministry of Justice,
not a s... Secluded lady in the inner chambers.
Of course she needs to meet guests
and handle official business.
Xing is virtuous indeed.
Although Xing's not my biological child,
I watched her grow up.
Everyone knows that.
Before, when she married Shen Du,
I was also really worried.
I also hoped
she could have a good marriage.
Now that
she's divorced and returned to the Yan family,
she should at least consider
the reputation of the Yan family.
What do you mean by that?
Don't you know?
The entire Yan family
is now being watched by the Imperial Investigation Department.
People outside are saying
that the Yan family's daughter
has become a discarded woman.
Now, if male outsiders come and go as they please,
I'm afraid people will think
that our Yan family is not strict in discipline.
First Madam!
Obviously, it was Xing
who didn't want that
ungrateful Shen Du anymore.
How dare you call our Xing
a discarded woman?
Let me tell you, First Madam!
I've put up with you for a long time.
I'll fight you, I will!
I only have good intentions.
What do you mean good intentions?
Stop fighting! Stop fighting!
Come on, stop fighting!
Stop it!
What a family misfortune.
Both of you, stop it right now!
Xing.
I'm only being kind, yet you...
You... You be quiet too!
Mother. Madam.
Please stop arguing.
Father.
We need to go out for a while.
Ru!
-You're talking nonsense!
-Look!
Isn't that a male outsider?
Stop fighting!
You're still trying to deny it?
Honey!
Why are you hitting me now?
Look at her!
Are you going to do something about her or not?
Be gentler. You hit my face!
You are...
You're from Tongming House?
Are you Yan Xing?
Turn around the corner ahead,
and there's a small alley.
You can leave through there.
No one will know.
Why are you helping us?
For the sake of sisterhood,
and for the virtue of women.
Thanks a lot.
Hurry up and go.
They're here.
Sister.
Hurry, hurry.
Xing.
Chuichui.
Hurry up.
You're finally here.
I was worried you wouldn't be able to get out.
Fortunately,
it was a close call.
So White Ghost really
teamed up with Lai Luozhi?
From now on,
I will have no more dealings with Shen Du.
How did you manage to evade
the eyes and ears of the Imperial Investigation Department?
You haven't left the mansion for days,
which has made Lai Luozhi
lower their guard a bit.
It seems Chuichui
understood my letter.
Salt has eyes and ears.
Three days by the pond.
[Salt has eyes and ears. Three days by the pond.]
It means there are Lai Luozhi's spies
monitoring around the Yan's Mansion.
It says to
meet you at the pawnshop three days later.
Lu Chuichui
is already waiting for us at the pawnshop.
Let's find a way
to bypass the hidden sentries.
[Salt has eyes and ears. Three days by the pond.]
Gift to Zhanxin.
So she is
the sister of Kuang Zhanxin from Tongming House.
Did she help me today
because she thought
I had cleared Kuang Zhanxin's name?
Investigating cases and clearing names
was never about seeking rewards.
What we gained today
is all due to people's kind intentions
and mutual support.
[Gift to Zhanxin]
Chuichui.
Nowadays, Lai Luozhi has absolute power.
I've come up with an idea.
Why don't you and Jiang Langxing
leave Xiang'an for a while
and lay low for a bit?
I pretended to go along with him yesterday.
He should be letting his guard down recently.
We can take this opportunity
to run away.
Xing.
Why don't you leave here with us?
I need to stay here.
Why?
Don't tell me you still can't let go of
that White Ghost.
Take care of yourself.
Chuichui.
Father.
It's your first time traveling far from home.
Remember,
nothing is as good as gold.
I've
prepared some extra gold for you.
It'll be convenient for your journey.
Come on, put it on your back.
Be careful on the road.
Be good.
Father.
Alright, be good.
[Lu's Pawnshop]
Nerd!
Chuichui.
It's alright. It's alright.
Nerd.
For my sake,
you have to leave Xiang'an
and give up your identity as a constable.
Do you feel any regret,
or think it's a pity?
As long as you're by my side,
anywhere
can be a place
where I, Jiang Langxing, can make a difference.
Right.
From now on,
we'll be a pair of
righteous heroes, punishing evil and upholding justice in the martial world.
Sure.
Thanks a lot.
Take care.
Farewell.
Let me take that.
What do you mean she's gone!
I am incompetent, My Lord.
Miss Lu and Jiang Langxing
have indeed disappeared without a trace.
I'm afraid they've already left Xiang'an.
Then go out of the city
and search everywhere!
Even if you have to dig three feet into the ground,
you must find her and bring her to me!
Yes, My Lord!
She was deceiving you all along.
A woman like that,
why do you still care about her?
Get out!
All of you, get out!
Dongzhou Garrison,
[Lai's Mansion]
here to pay respects to Lord Lai.
The prefect of Yangle City requests an audience with Lord Lai.
The commander of Yuanmeng City is here to pay respects.
My Lord.
The carriages of noble families
who have come to pledge allegiance in recent days
have blocked the streets in front of the mansion
so tightly that not even water can pass through.
They won't leave even if we try to drive them away.
Now,
70 percent of the officials
have already pledged allegiance to you.
Scholars alone won't be enough for me to achieve great things.
Any movements from those local military leaders?
The commanders of local garrison troops of various regions
have sent their calling cards,
expressing
their desire to take the opportunity of the Grand Court Assembly
to come to Xiang'an and pay their respects to you, My Lord.
Good.
Of the six garrison commanders,
four have already pledged their allegiance.
The remaining two are not to be feared.
The second day of the second lunar month.
It seems
the second day of the second lunar month
is an auspicious day.
Moths to a flame!
Born at dawn, dead by dusk!
Not entering the cycle of reincarnation!
Immortal reincarnation!
The Purple Star has appeared.
A blessing for the Cang State.
Sacred grace has arrived.
The world belongs to Luozhi!
Sacred grace has arrived!
Xing.
Pan.
The Imperial Investigation Department
hasn't yet withdrawn
their surveillance on the Yan's Mansion.
Coming out like this,
aren't you afraid of being implicated?
If Lai Luozhi wants to implicate me,
would it matter if I come out once or twice?
I'm just accompanying you on a walk to take your mind off things.
What's wrong with that?
I heard that
the Imperial Security Bureau and the Imperial Investigation Department
are now in cahoots.
From now on, I'm afraid
there will be no more just officials in Xiang'an.
Being immersed in rumors
can be harmful to your health.
Why don't we go find some fun instead?
Madam?
Yan... Director Yan.
Director Yan.
I remember you claimed to be
fully dedicated to your official duties.
How come nowadays I can't find you
at the Ministry of Justice,
but instead see you here
flirting with someone irrelevant?
Lord Shen.
Xing has finished her shift.
She's under the Ministry of Justice.
Who she talks to and who she associates with
is not under the jurisdiction of the Imperial Security Bureau, I'm afraid.
Among all the officials in the court of the Cang State,
except for the Imperial Investigation Department,
who dares not to listen to
what the Imperial Security Bureau says?
Shen Du.
Look at what you've become now.
The common people are saying,
[Ministry of Justice]
"The Black and White Kings of Hell walk side by side.
From now on, the mortal world is a purgatory."
Do you think
being avoided by everyone like a venomous snake
is something to be proud of?
Do you still remember
the words you once said
and the vows you once made?
People
all change.
Xing.
Don't waste your words on this kind of person.
Let's go.
[Ministry of Justice]
Xing.
Sit here and rest for a while.
I'll be right out.
Xing.
Do you remember
this is where
we first met?
The inversion of shadows,
the intersection of light,
and the creation of focus and shadows are what is known
as the principle of focus.
This is what you taught me.
From the moment we first met,
I've pictured
what you would become in the future.
You would become
a female official who speaks for the people,
leaving a lasting legacy.
Now, only you
still believe in the aspirations in my heart.
In my eyes,
you've never been someone's daughter
or someone's wife.
You are Yan Xing, a female official of the Ministry of Justice,
the most skilled
crime-solver in the Cang State,
and more importantly, my soulmate.
I only hope
that you can fulfill your ambitions
in the Ministry of Justice freely and happily.
I'll definitely
stand silently behind you.
But unfortunately,
everything has changed now.
The court is full of undercurrents,
with no fairness or justice to speak of.
You mediate within it,
only to be burdened by it.
The world is vast,
and there are many paths of life
besides being an official.
Perhaps you're right.
With our combined strength,
even if we travel the four seas,
we can right wrongs
and clear unjust accusations.
Yan Xing.
Are you willing to come with me,
escape this land of right and wrong,
and journey to the ends of the earth together?
If you're willing,
I can
take the lives
of that despicable couple right now.
If you let go now,
I'm afraid she'll never come back.
Perfect.
It's better not to have them in my sight.
Rest assured.
I will have the Ministry of Justice clear the Shen family's name.
It's just a matter of filing a petition.
Is there anything else you need to tell your family?
I've already told my family
that I'm going out to travel for a while.
They highly approve,
believing that the world is vast,
and it will naturally broaden my mind,
freeing me from worldly troubles.
Once we leave the city,
all the troubles
will have nothing to do with us anymore.
With the sky as our roof and the ground as our bed,
we'll walk on clouds and ride the wind.
Your Majesty.
I'm alright.
It's okay.
Your Majesty!
Gua...
Your Majesty.
Please take your medicine.
News from the palace says that
the Grand Empress Dowager's condition has worsened.
It seems that her days are numbered.
If that's the case,
I should personally pay her a visit.
Who is it?
I heard that your condition has worsened, Your Majesty,
and I am deeply concerned.
I've specially come to pay my respects and inquire about your health.
My condition is not serious.
A few days of rest will suffice.
Lord Lai, there's no need to worry.
Just focus on
your duties at court.
Behave yourself,
lest people say you don't know your place.
Your admonition is correct, Your Majesty.
It seems
the news about of your
grave illness
is not unfounded, Your Majesty.
How dare you!
In my presence,
how dare you be so disrespectful?
Don't get angry.
Your life hangs by a thread.
Guards! Guards!
You've come to harm me.
Your Majesty.
How could I have such intentions?
This humble servant has always been
loyal and devoted.
Lai Luozhi.
You were born of humble origins.
If it weren't for my patronage,
how could you have achieved
your current wealth and status?
Yet you've harbored treasonous thoughts.
You are truly worse than a beast.
If it weren't for your own
suspicion and jealousy,
being unable to tolerate others,
how could you have met with such retribution today?
I can face heaven and earth with a clear conscience.
I have no guilt in my heart,
and I have not failed the Cang State!
How dare you judge me!
What a fine claim of a clear conscience.
Then do you remember
Consort Shu whom you framed
and drove to her death?
Consort Shu?
Who are you really?
What is your relationship with her?
Indeed.
In this vast imperial palace,
who would remember
a woman offered by a neighboring country,
a living,
breathing consort who was driven to death?
Sure enough,
even fewer would remember
her child.
Luozhi.
You must remember,
it's Zhou Xu who's going to kill your mother.
Now that your father died,
in this entire palace,
there's no longer
a way for the two of us to survive.
The Empress and
the Zhou clan behind her
have absolute power.
They will not
allow you to live.
But don't be afraid.
I will protect you.
Even if I die,
I will make sure you survive.
I'll trade my life
for your chance to live, Son.
Luozhi.
You must survive.
You must live on,
to reclaim everything that belongs to you.
Do you understand?
Luozhi...
The wet nurse traded her son's life
for mine.
From then on, I became Lai Luozhi
and lived with the wet nurse's twin daughters,
relying on each other.
Mother!
People laugh at moths flying into the fire,
unaware they are mayflies!
Mother!
After my mother died,
you, the high and mighty
Grand Empress Dowager, thought
this was nothing more than
a harem scandal.
You ordered the palace
not to discuss this matter anymore.
It was also because of this
that the maid who came to the Cang State
with my mother,
my wet nurse,
managed to evade everyone's attention
and take me out of the palace.
So
back then,
in the ruins,
that charred body of a boy...
The wet nurse's son
was right about my age.
He voluntarily
walked into that fire instead of me.
Madness.
This is pure madness.
All of this
is thanks to you.
You are the cause,
so it should be me
who repays you with this consequence.
What do you want to do?
Your life is coming to an end now,
and that young emperor is still not of age.
I think this empire
should be handed over to me,
his uncle.
This throne was mine in the first place.
Only by my ascension can we better continue
the bloodline of the Xiao family.
My father's spirit in heaven
would also feel gratified
on behalf of our ancestors.
Please write
the abdication edict now, Your Majesty.
Abdication edict?
Wishful thinking.
Think about it.
My sister Yong'an
is still imprisoned.
And as for Prince Xian,
it's time to arrange
a good place for him to go, too.
You dare!
I only became the regent
because you fully supported me,
right, Your Majesty?
The evidence of Yong'an's treason by supporting the army
is overwhelming.
From Minister Zhang,
I can also easily dig up
a crime to imprison Prince Xian.
It would be painless.
As for what will happen next,
Your Majesty,
can you really not think of it?
I
entered the palace at 14.
My entire life
has been spent in fights and struggles.
But in the end,
I still let my guard down.
You could have waited until after my death.
Any kind of edict
could have been fabricated at your will, couldn't it?
You're just
someone seeking fame and reputation.
You just want to legitimately
ascend to this position, that's all.
The day of the Grand Court Assembly
is also the death anniversary of my mother.
It's also the final deadline
I've set for you.
By then,
my mother will witness her son
return openly and righteously.
Her death anniversary
will be the day her child ascends to the throne!
Shen Du.
I know what you're up to.
Counting the days,
she should have arrived.
[Nanlang State]
This is the boundary stone of Nanlang.
We've finally arrived.
Master.
Lord Chen?
My disciple.
[Nanlang State]
I received your urgent letter
and calculated that you should have arrived by now.
I didn't expect you to be even quicker.
Master.
Now, Xiang'an City
is crawling with Lai Luozhi's pawns.
For safety's sake,
we didn't dare to stop along the way.
[Nanlang State]
The information you want to know
is indeed not simple.
So Xing,
you'd already asked Lord Chen
to secretly come to Nanlang
[Lai Luozhi's mother's tombstone only bears the name Bi Luo]
to investigate Lai Luozhi's background.
[Bi Luo]
I heard from Chuichui before
that on the tombstone of Lai Luozhi's mother,
there was only the name Bi Luo,
but no family surname.
So I asked Yeyun to investigate.
On the unburnt paper offerings,
there were drawings of conch shells.
On the joss paper used in ancestral worship in the Cang State,
such patterns are rarely seen.
However, I've heard that in Nanlang,
there are people who worship conch shells.
Yeyun also found
traces of spilled ox blood on the ground.
Using ox blood for sacrifice
is also precisely a custom of Nanlang.
Master.
So Bi Luo was actually Consort Shu,
whom Nanlang offered to the late emperor of the Cang State?
That's correct.
However, this Bi Luo
had a part of her past
that is unknown to others.
I'm afraid even her own son
doesn't know about it.
After tomorrow's Grand Court Assembly,
everything will be settled.
After waiting for so many years,
if she obediently
hands over the throne tomorrow,
there'll still be something missing.
[Cangming Hall]
Long live the Emperor!
The envoy from Xichen presents tribute.
The envoy from Nanlang presents tribute.
Today,
all states have come to pay tribute,
joining in this grand occasion.
May we foster friendly relations between states,
and bring peace to all corners of the world.
With a strong foundation, the state will be at peace.
We should start anew with the people,
and unite the hearts of all under heaven.
Only then can we shine for a thousand years.
To maintain longevity,
select only the worthy for office,
and the world will naturally be set in order.
To unite all under heaven
and maintain longevity
is the responsibility of a great state.
Greetings, Your Majesty!
Long live the Grand Empress Dowager!
The Court Assembly is a grand occasion.
The whole world rejoices.
Her Majesty is delighted
and has recovered from her illness.
She hereby wants to bestow a feast upon all court officials.
Thank you for your great kindness, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, you've just recovered.
You shouldn't overexert yourself.
If your old illness relapses,
that would be terrible.
Your Majesty, do you have an edict
that's to be announced at the Grand Court Assembly
to all the officials?
Lord Lai.
You really are getting more and more disrespectful.
Thanks to your reminder, Mr. Lai.
I do have something to announce.
A few days ago, I suddenly fell ill with a severe ailment
and had no time for court affairs.
Many matters
were temporarily entrusted to the Imperial Investigation Department.
Mr. Lai has been working very hard.
Now,
I have fully recovered.
His Majesty is also studying
the art of governance with the Grand Tutor.
From this day forward,
Mr. Lai, you no longer need to perform
the duties of regent.
You are relieved of your burdensome duties at the Imperial Investigation Department.
Go and rest peacefully.